algoriddim.com 2019-05-14

# Algoriddim » Privacy Policy » Privacy

At Algoriddim your Privacy is important to us when you visit our websites or use the services of our djay product line. We appreciate that you put your trust in us, when you provide us your personal information. That’s why we would like to inform you transparently in this Privacy Policy which data we collect and how we use it.

### 1\. Data controller

algoriddim GmbH   
legally represented by the managing director Karim Morsy   
Königinstr. 33, 80539 Munich, Germany   
Email: [info@algoriddim.com](mailto:info@algoriddim.com)

### 2\. What data we collect and what we use it for

Depending on which of our services you use, we collect and process different data. In the following we will inform you which data we collect when you use the respective service.

#### 2.1 Visiting our websites

When you visit our website, we only collect the information that your browser provides to us. This includes, but is not limited to, your IP address, the date and time of the re-quest, transferred data volume, web browser, operating system, language and ver-sion of the browser. We use the data to provide you a better experience when visiting our website based on our legitimate interest in optimizing the website.

#### 2.2 Using the apps of our djay product line

When you use one of our apps we collect data from the device on which you installed our app. In particular, we collect the hard- and software configuration of your device, your IP-address, your device ID and advertisement ID (only mobile devices), your app settings and functions used, the frequency, time and duration of your usage and error notifications. We use your data based on the fulfilment of our contractual duties to provide you the services requested.

#### 2.3 Further data processing

If you contact us by email, the personal data transmitted to us in your email will be stored. The data are only used to answer your questions.

If you want to use our forum, you have to log in to a 'GetSatisfaction' account. We op-erate our forum with the help of our partner getsatisfaction. Getsatisfaction provides us with your email address. Please remember that activity on our forum is public. For more information, see the getsatisfaction privacy policy.

If your licensed product contains a product key, you can voluntarily register your pur-chased app with us in order to store your license data in our database. We collect your name, email address, country, zip code and license key. In addition, you can store information about your specific usage behavior.

### 3\. With whom we share data

Personal data is only transmitted to third parties such as service providers where necessary for the purpose of the provision of their services. If personal data is trans-ferred to third countries, we take appropriate measures to ensure that these third par-ties comply with an adequate level of protection for personal data.

We might share your data with

  * service suppliers who carry out services on our behalf
  * competent authorities in order to ensure compliance with applicable laws
  * third parties in the course of a merger or acquisition.

In order to connect your Spotify account to our app as a source for your music, you agree that Spotify will provide the app the necessary information. This includes pub-licly accessible information, private playlists, subscription details, email address, saved titles, albums and shows. This information will only be processed within the app on your device and not be transferred to our servers. The data is used by the app to provide you the services requested based on the fulfilment of our contractual du-ties.

If you purchase the app through the online store via our website, the order will be processed by the service provider FastSpring. To place an order in our website online store FastSpring will process your name, address, email address and payment data. For more information, see the FastSpring privacy policy.

### 4\. When we delete data

Stored personal data shall be deleted if you revoke your consent to store your data, if your information is no longer required to achieve the purpose pursued by storing your data or if the storage of your data is / becomes inadmissible for other legal reasons.

The data retention period changes on the basis of circumstances such as: the type of data, reason for collection and processing, and relevant legal requirements.

### 5\. Newsletter

If you would like to read about the latest and greatest on our djay product line you can sign up to our newsletter.

By registering (via a double opt-in process) for the newsletter, you agree to receive the newsletter. The data collected will only be used to send the newsletter. Our newsletter is sent via Mailchimp. Please note that Mailchimp may transfer personal data outside of the EU. Please contact Mailchimp with any questions or concerns about this.

You may revoke your consent to receive the newsletter and the collection and storage of data associated therewith at any time. You can revoke your consent by following this link, or by using a link in the newsletters, or by an informal note to algoriddim GmbH, Königinstr. 33, 80539 Munich, Germany, or by email to [info@algoriddim.com](mailto:info@algoriddim.com).

### 6\. Cookies and other technologies

We use temporary session cookies and permanent cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored on your device which enable analysis of the use of the app. We use cookies and other data collection tools to capture data that helps us to personalize and optimize our services.

#### 6.1 Cookies we use on our website

##### 6.1.1 Google Analytics

We use “Google Analytics”, a web analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States of America (hereinafter referred to as: “Google"). Google uses cookies, i.e., small text files that are stored on your end device which permit analysis of your use of our website. The information produced by the cookie regarding usage of our website is usually transferred to a server of Google in the United States of America and saved there. If anonymization of the IP address transmitted by the cookie is activated on the website (“IP Anonymization”), your IP address will be shortened by Google within the Member States of the European Un-ion or in other states party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional circumstances, will your full IP address be transferred to a server of Goo-gle in the United States of America and abbreviated there. Google will use this infor-mation to evaluate your use of our website on our behalf, to compile reports on the website use, and to render further services connected to website use and internet use vis-à-vis us. While doing so, pseudonymous usage profiles can be compiled from the processed data. The IP address transmitted using Google Analytics will not be com-bined with any other data of Google. We use Google Analytics only with the activated IP Anonymization described above. This means that your IP address will be further processed only after being shortened by Google. In this way, reference to a person can be avoided.

You can prevent storage of the cookies produced by Google Analytics by altering the corresponding settings in your web browser. Please note that, in this case, you may be unable to use all functions of our website. If you want to prevent collection of the data generated by the cookie and reference to your user behavior (including your IP address) and processing of this data by Google, you can click here to opt-out or download and install the web browser plug-in available under the following link: tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

You can find further information concerning terms of use and data protection at <https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/gb.html> and <https://policies.google.com/?hl=en>.

##### 6.1.2 Google Tag Manager

We use “Google Tag Manager”, a service of Google Inc. Google Tag Manager allows us to manage web page tags from a single interface. The tool Google Tag Manager, which implements the tags, is a cookie-free domain and does not collect any personal data itself. Google Tag Manager triggers other tags that may collect data. Google Tag Manager does not access this data. If deactivated at domain or cookie level, the de-activation will remain in effect for all tracking tags implemented with Google Tag Manager.

##### 6.1.3 Facebook Custom Audiences

We use “Facebook Custom Audiences”, a remarketing service of Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, California 94304, United States of America (hereinafter designated as: “Facebook”). Facebook Custom Audiences enables us to display in-terest-based advertisements, so-called "Facebook ads", to visitors of our website when they visit the social network Facebook or other websites that also use Face-book Custom Audiences. By using "Facebook Custom Audiences", your web browser automatically establishes a direct connection to the Facebook server. We have no control over the extent and further use of data collected through Facebook Custom Audiences. To the best of our knowledge, Facebook receives information that you have visited the relevant part of our website or clicked on an ad on our website. If you have a Facebook account and are registered, Facebook can associate the visit with your user account. Even if you are not registered with Facebook or have not logged in, Facebook may obtain and store your IP address and other identifying information.

Facebook Custom Audiences can be deactivated by logged-in users at <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads#_> . Please note that this setting will be deleted if you delete your cookies.

Please visit the following pages for further information concerning the purpose and scope of the data collection and Facebook's further processing and use of the data as well as your configuration options to protect your privacy:   
<https://www.facebook.com/ads/website_custom_audiences/>   
<https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>

##### 6.1.4 Facebook Connect

We use “Facebook Connect”, a service of Facebook Inc. Facebook Connect makes it easier to register for services on the internet. Instead of using a registration form on our website, you can enter your login data for Facebook and then use our services. By using "Facebook Connect", your web browser automatically establishes a direct connection to the Facebook server. You will be redirected to the Facebook page to log in. There you can log in with your user data. This will link your Facebook account to our service. We have no control over the extent and further use of data collected through Facebook's use of Facebook Connect. To the best of our knowledge, Facebook receives information that you have visited the relevant part of our website or clicked on an ad on our website. If you have a Facebook account and are registered, Facebook can associate the visit with your user account. Even if you are not registered with Facebook or have not logged in, Facebook may still obtain and store your IP address and other identifying information.

You can prevent the processing of the above information by Facebook by using our registration form and not using Facebook Connect. You can revoke your consent at any time. The legality of the data processing already carried out remains unaffected by the revocation.

#### 6.2 Technologies we use in our apps

##### 6.2.1 Firebase

We use Firebase, a service of Google Inc. (hereinafter referred to as: “Firebase”). Firebase allows us to carry out analysis on information which is gathered by our apps. Device information and other information which we gather is provided to Google in order to enable them to carry out data analysis.

For further information on how Google's Firebase analytics tool uses data, please see the site "How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps", (located at <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>).

##### 6.2.2 Crashlytics

We use Crashlytics, a service by Google Inc (hereinafter referred to as: “Crashlytics”). Crashlytics is a crash reporting service. For these crash reports, certain information about the crash such as device type, operating system version and some technical data about the mobile device is sent to Crashlytics. No personal data is transmitted and no conclusions can be drawn about specific persons. This analysis program uses anonymous IP addresses of users for analysis purposes.

For more information about the data collected by Crashlytics, please see <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>. 

##### 6.2.3 Flurry Analytics

We use Flurry Analytics, a service by Flurry Inc., 2S2 2nd St #202, San Francisco, CA 94105, USA (hereinafter referred to as: “Flurry Analytics”). Flurry Analytics en-ables analysis of the performance and usage of the app. The information generated by Flurry about the performance and usage of the app is usually transferred to a Flurry server and stored there.

For more information on the privacy practices and policies please visit the Privacy Policy page of Flurry Analytics: You can opt-out from Flurry Analytics service to pre-vent Flurry Analytics from using and sharing your information by visiting Flurry Analyt-ics' opt-out page: <https://dev.flurry.com/secure/optOut.do>

##### 6.2.4 Facebook App Events

We use the Facebook SDK service called “Facebook App Events”, a service by Facebook Inc. (hereinafter referred to as: “Facebook App Events”). Facebook App Events helps us to evaluate the reach of our advertising campaigns and use of Face-book SDK. Facebook provides us with an aggregated analysis of user behavior with our app. You can opt out of using Facebook App Events by changing your app set-tings. For more information, please see <https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy>.

##### 6.2.5 CloudKit

We use Apple CloudKit, a service by Apple Inc., One Apple Park Way, Cupertino, California, USA, 95014 (hereinafter referred to as: “CloudKit”). CloudKit enables us to sync data between your Apple devices (iPhone, iPad and Apple Watch). Your data is stored in a private database, which is encrypted with an account-based key. There-fore, we do not have access to any data stored in your iCloud account. We also do not have access to your Apple ID - only a unique identifier that is limited in scope to just our app. It is not possible to track your identity between apps with this identifier.

You can revoke access to iCloud and delete all your data in the iOS Settings app on your iOS device.

For more information, see Apple’s privacy policy: <https://www.apple.com/legal/privacy>. 

### 7\. How we protect your data

We will protect your personal data from risks associated with data processing, particularly unauthorized access, use or disclosure. We maintain appropriate technical and organizational measures for this purpose

### 8\. Your rights

#### 8.1 Right to withdraw consent

You have the right to withdraw the consent that you have given to process your per-sonal data at any time with effect for the future.

Withdrawal does not affect the lawfulness of the processing based on your consent which has occurred up until revocation. 

#### 8.2 Right of access

You have the right to demand information concerning your stored personal data free of charge. At your request, this information can also be provided electronically.

#### 8.3 Right to rectification, erasure and restriction of processing

You have the right to demand the rectification and the erasure of, or the restriction of the processing of your personal data. However, if your data is erased or blocked, you can no longer use the relevant services.

Your right to erasure can be precluded by statutory retention obligations.

#### 8.4 Right to data portability

You have the right for us to provide you or other controllers, in machine-readable form, with data which we process in automated processes or to the processing of which you have agreed.

#### 8.5 Enforcement of rights

You can exercise your rights by informal communication to algoriddim GmbH, Königinstr. 33, 80539 Munich, Germany or by email to [info@algoriddim.com](mailto:info@algoriddim.com).

Should you have a complaint, you may also contact the competent supervisory authority for data protection.

As of: November 2018
